<?xml version="1.0"?>
<quiz>
    <q flash="y">
        <content>
	    What is a moral code? 
        </content>
    
        <explanation>
	    A moral code is a list of rules for behavior. Any list
	    of rules for behavior counts as a moral code.
        </explanation>
    </q>
    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What are the two claims that Moral Universalism makes?
        </content>
    
        <explanation>
	    1. There is at least one objectively true moral rule that it is morally wrong for anyone to break regardless of whether they accept the rule.

	    2. Objectively true moral rules never change. 
        </explanation>
    </q>
    <q flash="y">
        <content>
           What are the two claims that Cultural Relativism makes? 
        </content>
    
        // use the a snippet here to add answers
    
        <explanation>
            1. It is objectively morally wrong to break any moral rule accepted by your society or culture.

	    2. There are no moral rules that all societies and cultures must accept.
        </explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What are the three main attractions of Cultural Relativism?
        </content>
        
        <explanation>
	    1. It offers an easy escape from Moral Skepticism.
	    
	    2. It offers a way to understand how different answers to moral questions can be right for different people.
            
	    3. It seems to promote tolerance. 
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    Why does Cultural Relativism seem to offer an easy escape from Moral Skepticism? Also, does 
	    Cultural Relativism really promote tolerance --- what if your society believes it should impose
	    its beliefs on everyone else? What would Cultural Relativism say you ought to do in that situation?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What does Moral Skepticism say?
        </content>
    
        <explanation>
	    It is impossible to *know* the answer to *any* moral question.
        </explanation>
    </q>
    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Disagreement Argument Against Moral Universalism?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
            P1)	People disagree about morality even after lots of debate.

	    P2) If people disagree about morality even after lots of debate, then everyone's moral beliefs are equally correct.

	    P3) If everyone's moral beliefs are equally correct, then there is no True Moral Code.

	    C)	Therefore, there is no True Moral Code.

        </explanation>
	<study>
	    Which premise(s) do defenders of Moral Universalism deny and why?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Observation Argument Against Moral Universalism?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
	    P1)	Moral questions cannot be answered by any experiment or observation. 

	    P2)	If moral questions cannot be answered by any experiment or observation, then they have no real answers. 

	    P3)	If moral questions have no real answers, then there is no True Moral Code.

	    C)	Therefore, there is no True Moral Code.

	    
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    Which premise(s) do defenders of Moral Universalism deny and why?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
	    What is a moral intuition supposed to be?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
	    A clear mental perception of an objective moral truth. 

	    Intuitions can come in degrees of strength.
        </explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Undeniable Wrongs Argument Against Cultural Relativism?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
	    P1)	Some actions are never okay to do, even if your society accepts them. 

	    P2) If Cultural Relativism is true, then any action is okay to do if your society accepts it. 

	    C)	Therefore, Cultural Relativism is false. 
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    What is the argument form here?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Moral Progress Argument Against Cultural Relativism?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    P1)	If Cultural Relativism is true, then societies can change, but cannot morally improve.

	    P2)	But some societies can and do morally improve.

	    C)	Therefore, Cultural Relativism is false. 
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    What is the argument form here?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the One Person Many Cultures Argument Against Cultural Relativism?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    P1) Each person belongs to many societies and cultures, none of which is "morally special." 

	    P2) If each person belongs to many societies and cultures, none of which is "morally special", 
	    then no one society or culture determines what moral code a person must follow.

	    P3) If no one society or culture that determines what moral code a person must follow, then Cultural Relativism is false. 

	    C) Therefore, Cultural Relativism is false.
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    What is the argument form here?    
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What does Individual Relativism say?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
            1. It is objectively morally wrong to break any moral rule you accept.

	    2. There are no moral rules you are in any sense required to accept.
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    Why is this theory especially hard to accept? What are its implications?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q>
        <content>
            Which of the following is a conditional moral rule?
        </content>
        <answer correct="1">
	    If you are in a country where wearing shoes inside a person's home is considered disrespectful, you should take 
	    your shoes off when entering a stranger's home.
        </answer>
        
        <answer correct="0">
            Stealing is always morally wrong.
        </answer>

	<answer correct="0">
	    It is unconditionally morally wrong to lie.
	</answer>

	<answer correct="0">
	    It is always morally permissible to do what's required to save your own life.
	</answer>
        <explanation>
	    A conditional moral rule is a moral rule that asserts a moral requirement that is limited to
	    certain circumstances. They are usually stated with "if-then" (conditional) sentences,
	    but can be stated in other ways too. (E.g., it's wrong to kill unless you are a soldier in war.)
        </explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What does Divine Command Theory say?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
            1. Any time you do something objectively morally wrong, you have broken a divine command.

	    2. Any time you break a divine command, you have done something objectively morally wrong.
        </explanation>
	<study>
	    There are two versions of DCT corresponding to the two ways of responding to the Euthyphro question. What are they?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the DCT-Version of the Euthyphro Question?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
	    Are objectively morally wrong things wrong *because God commands us not to do them,*
	    or does God command us not to do objectively morally wrong things *because they are wrong?*
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    Does it make sense to answer "Both" here? Why or why not?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Argument With The Terrible Conclusion?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    P1) It is morally right and good to do whatever God commands, and what makes it morally right and good is just the fact that God commands it.

	    P2) God has the power to command any action, and for no reason other than to get us to prove our loyalty.

	    C) Therefore, God has the power to make it morally right to torture an innocent baby just to prove our loyalty. 
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    What are the three responses to this argument discussed in class?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What are the three reasons the Bible is not a complete and easy guide to all of morality?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
            1. Commands in the Bible are sometimes obscure. (E.g., the "unforgiveable sin".)

	    2. Some important moral topics are never directly discussed in the Bible. (E.g., abortion.)

	    3. The Bible's commands sometimes seem morally questionable or even clearly incorrect. (E.g., never resisting evil.)
        </explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What does Psychological Egoism say?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    It is impossible to have an
	    unselfish motivation for one’s actions, feelings,
	    and emotions.
	    In other words, all motivation is
	    inherently selfish. 
	</explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Argument From Reinterpretation?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    P1) We can imagine a selfish motivation for any action.

	    P2) If we can imagine a selfish motivation for any action, then motivation is always selfish.

	    C) Therefore, motivation is always selfish.
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    What is the argument form here? What is the problem with this argument?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
	    What is the Pleasure-Seeker Argument for Psychological Egoism?            
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    P1) If everyone always tries to maximize pleasure for themselves, then everyone’s motivation is always selfish.

	    P2) Everyone always tries to maximize pleasure for themselves.

	    C) Therefore, everyone’s motivation is always selfish.
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    How can an opponent of Psychological Egoism respond to this argument? Which premise will they deny and why?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
	    What is the Desire-Seeker Argument for Psychological Egoism?            
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    P1) If everyone always tries to satisfy their desires, then everyone’s motivation is always selfish.

	    P2) Everyone always tries satisfy their desires.

	    C) Therefore, everyone’s motivation is always selfish.     
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    How can an opponent of Psychological Egoism respond to this argument? Which premise will they deny and why?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What does Moral Nihilism say?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
            Nothing is ever objectively morally wrong.
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    Why is this view hard to swallow?
	</study>
    </q>
</quiz>
