<?xml version="1.0"?>
<quiz>
    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Universe History Well-being Level? How is it defined?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
            The "UHWL" is the sum total of the Lifetime Well-being Levels ("LWLs")
	    of every being that exists, has existed, and ever will exist in the
	    entire history of the universe.
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    If the UHWL is positive, does that mean the number of beings in 
	    the history of the universe with a positive LWL is greater than
	    the number with a negative LWL? Why or why not?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What does Utilitarianism say?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
	    Utilitarianism says that an action is objectively morally wrong
	    if and only if there is something else
	    you could do that would result in a higher
	    Universe History Well-being Level.
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    Does Utilitarianism always tell us to benefit as many people
	    as possible? Why or why not?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
	<content>
	    What will Utilitarianism say if there
	    are two or more actions that would each result in
	    the same UHWL, but no other action would
	    result in higher UHWL than them?
	</content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
	    Utilitarianism says it’s permissible to do any of those two or more actions.
        </explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
	<content>
	    What will Utilitarianism say if all of your
	    options would result in negative UHWL, but some
	    would result in less negative UHWL than others?
	</content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    Utilitarianism will say to perform an
	    option that will result in the least negative
	    UHWL compared with the alternatives.
	</explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What does the "No Guidance" objection to Utilitarianism say?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    It says this: *It seems that a moral theory should
	    be useful. It should give us real-world guidance.
	    But Utilitarianism seems like it will typically be useless, since we
	    typically can’t know what action would result in the highest UHWL.*
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    What are the two responses to this objection that a utilitarian
	    could make that we discussed in class?
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the "Best Intentions" objection to Utilitarianism?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    The Best Intentions objection
	    says: *If Utilitarianism is true, then failing to raise the UHWL as much as you can
	    is objectively immoral. But no! An act is not wrong when 
	    the person doing it can't predict the outcome 
	    and is acting with good intent. So, Utilitarianism is false.*
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    What is the response to this discussed in class? (Hint: wrong versus blame...)
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What does a "Rights Theorist" in ethics believe?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
	    Rights Theorists claim that there are certain rights that all people have simply because
	    they are people. These rights are known as *moral rights* (sometimes
	    they are called *human* rights). 

	    Moral rights are supposed to be shared by all people;
	    they are not dependent on the laws of any government and cannot be taken away by any government.

	    Rights Theorists disagree about exactly which rights are moral rights, but
	    they mostly agree that our moral rights include the
	    right to life, the right to liberty, the right to fair and equal 
	    treatment by governments, and the right to not be held in slavery or servitude.
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    A famous Rights Theorist document outlining a number of supposed moral
	    rights is the UN Human Rights Declaration, which you can 
	    find [here](https://www.un.org/en/about-us/universal-declaration-of-human-rights).
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
	    What is the Angry Mob case and how is it used to challenge Utilitarianism 
	    using moral rights?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    In the Angry Mob case someone has killed the town’s beloved schoolteacher. 
	    The townspeople all think that Jones did it. Jones is hiding in the 
	    sheriff's office. Some people in the town have formed a mob. 

	    If the sheriff shoots Jones and hands over the body, the mob will disperse. 
	    If the sheriff lets the mob have Jones, they will tear him to pieces---a much more painful way to die. 
	    If the sheriff protects Jones, the mob will riot, several innocents (not members of the mob) will be killed, and many will be badly injured.

	    Utilitarianism says the sheriff must shoot Jones, since this both prevents the riot and
	    minimizes Jones's suffering. But many intuitively judge that the morally correct thing to do is to 
	    protect Jones, as this preserves Jones's rights, even though the UHWL will be lower.
	</explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Utility Monster objection to Utilitarianism?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
	<explanation>
	    You have five thousand pounds of rice you don’t need.

	    You could give one pound each to five thousand starving people,
	    which would result in +500,000 well-being added to the universe.

	    You could also give all five thousand pounds to the Utility
	    Monster, who will experience a +1,000,000 boost in well-being. 

	    Utilitarianism says the objectively morally correct thing to do
	    is to give the rice to the monster, since this will add more to the UHWL.

	    But to many it seems Utilitarianism's verdict is clearly wrong, 
	    since the intuitively moral thing to do is to feed the villagers.
	</explanation>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
	    Utilitarianism says that often the only morally acceptable lifestyle for someone
	    in the developed world is to donate all their discretionary 
	    income --- what's left after taxes and 
	    basic necessities are paid for --- to an effective charity. 

	    *Why does it say this?*
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
	    Often, the more needy a person is, the easier it is to raise 
	    their well-being level. (For example, a sandwich to a starving man
	    is a huge boost of well-being, but not much of a boost to someone well-fed and not hungry.
	    Another example: 50 cents means almost nothing to a typical American,
	    but to a child in a very poor nation, it can purchase a deworming pill that
	    will cure and prevent intestinal parasites for 6 months.)

	    Effective charities can therefore often create far more well-being per
	    dollar spent compared to what a typical American creates when spending on themselves.
	    Utilitarianism tells us we must maximize the well-being we create with our choices.
	    This implies we must often spend all non-essential money we make on effective charities.
        </explanation>

	<study>
	    To many this is a reason to reject Utilitarianism as "too demanding". But Utilitarians challenge
	    us to explain the difference between a child suffering in a developing country and 
	    a child dying right in front to us. To see how effective small donations can be, 
	    visit [this site](https://www.givewell.org/) or [this site](https://www.evidenceaction.org/).
	</study>
    </q>

    <q flash="y">
        <content>
            What is the Drowning Baby argument?
        </content>
        <!-- use the a snippet here to add answers for non-flash-cards -->
        <explanation>
            P1)	Common sense morality says it IS WRONG ignore a drowning baby in front of you just to avoid ruining new shoes.

	    P2)	Common sense morality says it IS NOT WRONG to ignore a starving child just to spend money on something besides charity.

	    P3)	There is no real morally important difference between these two children.

	    C)	Therefore, common sense morality is *inconsistent* and should be discarded in favor
	    of a consistent moral theory like Utilitarianism, which says 
	    we have a moral duty to both the drowning baby and the starving child.
	</explanation>

	<study>
	    To see how effective small donations can be, 
	    visit [this site](https://www.givewell.org/) or [this site](https://www.evidenceaction.org/).
	</study>
    </q>
</quiz>
